{"1":{"options":{"a":"Argumentative","b":"instructive","c":"Constructive","d":"destruction"},"question":"DIALECTIC","direction":"in  the  following  question,  choose  the  words  which  best  expresses  the  meaning  of  the capitalized word.","correctOption":"b"},"2":{"options":{"a":"Pile of legs","b":"heavy clock","c":"line of people placed as guard","d":"none of these"},"question":"CORDON","correctOption":"b"},"3":{"options":{"a":"Faint","b":"dainty","c":"delicious","d":"dormant"},"question":"FASTDIOUS","correctOption":"c"},"4":{"options":{"a":"Beginner","b":"murderer","c":"pattern","d":"fanatic"},"question":"Zealot","correctOption":"d"},"5":{"options":{"a":"Inconvenience","b":"nonsense","c":"blessing","d":"unreasonable"},"question":"NUISANCE","correctOption":"b"},"6":{"options":{"a":"Mange","b":"stipulate","c":"refuse","d":"dispensable"},"question":"AFFORD","direction":"select  the words which is closest to the opposite in meaning of the word in capital letters.","correctOption":"c"},"7":{"options":{"a":"Exceptional","b":"unusual","c":"dull","d":"plain"},"question":"EXTRAORDINARY","correctOption":"d"},"8":{"options":{"a":"Smart","b":"unusual","c":"dull","d":"plain"},"question":"LANGUID","correctOption":"b"},"9":{"options":{"a":"Indifferent","b":"detached","c":"determined","d":"irradiant"},"question":"PERINENT","correctOption":"d"},"10":{"options":{"a":"Dim","b":"clear","c":"Brittle","d":"clever"},"question":"LUMINIOUS","correctOption":"d"},"11":{"options":{"a":"At","b":"by","c":"from","d":"in"},"question":"She learned Russian ..................... the age of 25.","correctOption":"d"},"12":{"options":{"a":"About","b":"on","c":"to","d":"with"},"question":"What are you talking .........................?","correctOption":"c"},"13":{"options":{"a":"To","b":"on","c":"with","d":"of"},"question":"We are very proud ................ this company.","correctOption":"a"},"14":{"options":{"a":"Of","b":"on","c":"about","d":"with"},"question":"I'm sorry ............................... The job you didn't get.","correctOption":"b"},"15":{"options":{"a":"Of","b":"on","c":"to","d":"up"},"question":"We had to climb slowly ......................... The hill.","correctOption":"c"},"16":{"options":{"a":"Imbecility","b":"senility","c":"dotage","d":"Superannuation"},"question":"Extreme old age when a men behaves like a tool.","correctOption":"a"},"17":{"options":{"a":"Invisible","b":"intangible","c":"insensible","d":"unseen"},"question":"That which cannot be seen.","correctOption":"c"},"18":{"options":{},"correctOption":"b"},"19":{"options":{"a":"Do","b":"to do","c":"done","d":"did"},"question":"The teacher made her ......................his homework.","correctOption":"d"},"20":{"options":{},"correctOption":"a"},"21":{"options":{"a":"Less dependence on modern systems of communication","b":"More careful analysis of each news story and its value","c":"separating beans from junk","d":"Discriminating horrors from disasters"},"question":"Evaluation of news would imply","correctOption":"d"},"22":{"options":{"a":"Seems to be happy with the contemporary arrangements for circulating news","b":"Is shocked by the casual stories about horrors and disasters reported in the newspapers","c":"Wants better evaluation  of news before publication","d":"Wants to put his foot down on news stories."},"question":"The writer of the above passage","correctOption":"b"},"23":{"options":{"a":"Is  weak and often wanting entirely","b":"Deserves no one’s attention","c":"Should travel the wires","d":"Is junk dressed up as real news?"},"question":"In the above passage, the phrase amounts to a raw of beans  means that the news","correctOption":"a"},"24":{"options":{"a":"They do not separated the real news from mere sensations","b":"They have to accept whatever is received on the wires","c":"limited manpower makes serious evolution impossible","d":"people don’t see the difference between junk and real news"},"question":"Newspaper lack s Sense of discrimination because","correctOption":"d"},"25":{"options":{"a":"There has  to be censorship on news papers","b":"There is no point in having censorship","c":"Newspaper always dress up junk to look meaningful","d":"One has to be strict in selecting news items"},"question":"The passage implies that","correctOption":"a"},"26":{"options":{},"correctOption":"a"},"27":{"options":{"a":"290","b":"304","c":"385","d":"276"},"question":"A library has an average of 510 visitor on Sunday and 240 on other days. What is the average number of visitor per day in a month of 30 days beginning with a Sunday?","correctOption":"a"},"28":{"options":{"a":"none","b":"one","c":"two","d":"three"},"question":"If the digits of the number 5.726489 are arranged in ascending order, how many digits will remain at same position ?","correctOption":"b"},"29":{"options":{"a":"8","b":"10","c":"15","d":"20"},"question":"If 6 is 24% of a number , which is 40% of the same number?","correctOption":"b"},"30":{"options":{"a":"Rs 45,00","b":"Rs 44000","c":"42000","d":"40000"},"question":"A salary of an officer being increasing by 10% every year become Rs 48,400 in the third year .What was his original salary ?","correctOption":"a"},"31":{"options":{"a":"60","b":"72","c":"75","d":"80"},"question":"60 is 80% of which number?","correctOption":"c"},"32":{"options":{"a":"10,001","b":"10,010","c":"10,100","d":"11,000"},"question":"When 10,000 is increased by 0.1%, we get","correctOption":"b"},"33":{"options":{"a":"121","b":"231","c":"361","d":"661"},"question":"The square root of 130321 is","correctOption":"d"},"34":{"options":{"a":"72","b":"88","c":"108","d":"120"},"question":"Which of the following number is divisible by 12 but not by 8?","correctOption":"d"},"35":{"options":{"a":"16.6","b":"20","c":"25","d":"30"},"question":"The average of x and y is 40. If Z=10, what is the average of x,y and z?","correctOption":"c"},"36":{"options":{"a":"20l","b":"30l","c":"60l","d":"60l"},"question":"In mixture of 60litres the ratio of milk and water is 2:1.If This ratio is to be 1:2, then the quantity of water to be further added is","correctOption":"a"},"37":{"options":{"a":"1000","b":"1002","c":"1004","d":"1008"},"question":"The smallest four digit number by 6,8 and 16 is","correctOption":"d"},"38":{"options":{"a":"Rs 100","b":"Rs 120","c":"Rs 300","d":"400"},"question":"If a sum of money is divided equally among n children, each child will received Rs 60 .If another child is added to the group, then each child will receive Rs 50. What is the sum of money?","correctOption":"b"},"39":{"options":{"a":"2:5","b":"3:5","c":"4:5","d":"6:7"},"question":"Two number are respectively 20% and 50% more than a third number. The ratio of two number is","correctOption":"b"},"40":{"options":{"a":"5","b":"10","c":"9","d":"25"},"question":"If there are 5 routes for travelling two places A and B how many option are there for a person to travel from A to B and return back?","correctOption":"c"},"41":{"options":{"a":"100","b":"150","c":"625","d":"1250"},"question":"If 5a = 3b=25, then 30ab=?","correctOption":"c"},"42":{"options":{"a":"53","b":"54","c":"72","d":"75"},"question":"Arun obtained 76,65,82,67, and 85 marks  in English Mathematics .Chemistry .Biology& Physics .What is his average mark?","correctOption":"d"},"43":{"options":{"a":"0.00028","b":"0.0018","c":"0.018","d":"0.18"},"question":"0.3×0.006=","correctOption":"c"},"44":{"options":{"a":"9","b":"8","c":"6","d":"5"},"question":"If 8x+4=32, then 2x-1=?","correctOption":"a"},"45":{"options":{"a":"6log2","b":"log2","c":"3","d":"-1"},"question":"Value of log8÷log18  is","correctOption":"d"},"46":{"options":{"a":"413","b":"14","c":"12","d":"313"},"question":"A card is drawn at random from the pack of 52 card. What is the probability of getting a face card?","correctOption":"d"},"47":{"options":{"a":"√154","b":"1√15","c":"=14","d":"√15"},"question":"The value of cot휃 when sec휃=4 is","correctOption":"a"},"48":{"options":{"a":"A=∅","b":"B=∅","c":"(A∪B)=∅","d":"A=B"},"question":"A and B are two sets  AUB=A∩B, then","correctOption":"a"},"49":{"options":{"a":"2πr","b":"πr2","c":"πr2h","d":"2πr2"},"question":"The area of a circle is given by","correctOption":"b"},"50":{"options":{},"correctOption":"a"},"51":{"options":{"a":"Do not read as you weak sight.","b":"Do not speak as you are not asked to speak","c":"Do not play as you are hurt. d. Do not work as you are already overworke","d":""},"question":"Do not take sugar because you have diabetics is logically similar to.","correctOption":"c"},"52":{"options":{"a":"He can by costly things because he is a rich man.","b":"This us trivial so a fastidious person will not accept it","c":"he is unhappy as he has failed","d":"he has compassion for all because he is conscientine"},"question":"He will, tolerate insult because he is self-resistance is logically similar to","correctOption":"b"},"53":{"options":{"a":"There us a solution to every problem","b":"Determined persons can always find way outs for any problems","c":"Those who party can accomplish task","d":"we have to construct roads to enhance accessibility"},"question":"Where there us a will there is a way is logically similar to","correctOption":"a"},"54":{"options":{"a":"Wise people do not talks much","b":"foots generally praise themselves","c":"cowards die many times before their natural death","d":"Empty vessels and people are similar"},"question":"Empty vessels make much noise us logically similar to","correctOption":"c"},"55":{"options":{"a":"if you want to build your body take exercises","b":"speak to relieves you tension","c":"pay only when you have obtained services","d":"if you want to earn do not cheat other"},"question":"“Read in order to increase knowledge is logically similar to ”","correctOption":"a"},"56":{"options":{"a":"Frequently ;Occasionally","b":"Often :Constantly","c":"Constantly: Occasionally","d":"often: Really"},"question":"Always :Never","correctOption":"d"},"57":{"options":{"a":"psychiatrist : Maladjustment","b":"Teacher :School","c":"Scholar: Book","d":"Doctor: Diseases"},"question":"lawyer :Case","correctOption":"d"},"58":{"options":{"a":"Life: Death","b":"Trees: Forest","c":"Million: Billion","d":"large: Huge"},"question":"Crowd: Case","correctOption":"b"},"59":{"options":{},"correctOption":"c"},"60":{"options":{"a":"Increase: Decrease","b":"Infinity: Zero","c":"Digital: Series","d":"Multiplication: Division"},"question":"Plus: Minus","correctOption":"d"},"61":{"options":{"a":"here","b":"Now","c":"there","d":"nowhere"},"question":"","correctOption":"d"},"62":{"options":{"a":"Los Angeles","b":"Vancouver","c":"Acapulco","d":"cape Town"},"question":"","correctOption":"c"},"63":{"options":{"a":"Table tennis","b":"Gymnastics","c":"cheese","d":"volleyball"},"question":"","correctOption":"a"},"64":{"options":{"a":"30","b":"35","c":"36","d":"42"},"question":"","correctOption":"b"},"65":{"options":{"a":"listen","b":"Look","c":"View","d":"Watch"},"question":"","correctOption":"c"},"66":{"options":{"a":"Software","b":"CPU","c":"Monitors","d":"Modem"},"question":"Mortar: Engine:: Computer:?","direction":"Selection logically the best answer","correctOption":"a"},"67":{"options":{"a":"oil","b":"Power","c":"Monitor","d":"Worker"},"question":"People: Food :: Machines:?","correctOption":"b"},"68":{"options":{"a":"Understand","b":"Analyzer","c":"Decideq","d":"calculate"},"question":"Literacy : Ability to read and write :: Comprehend?","correctOption":"d"},"69":{"options":{},"correctOption":"c"},"70":{"options":{},"correctOption":"c"},"71":{"options":{},"correctOption":"a"},"72":{"options":{},"correctOption":"c"},"73":{"options":{},"correctOption":"c"},"74":{"options":{},"correctOption":"d"},"75":{"options":{},"correctOption":"b"},"76":{"options":{"a":"Baku","b":"Spain","c":"Brazil","d":"Cuba"},"question":"Which country is famous petroleum?","correctOption":"a"},"77":{"options":{"a":"Thailand","b":"India","c":"Cuba","d":"China"},"question":"Which country known as sugar Bowl in World?","correctOption":"c"},"78":{"options":{},"correctOption":"d"},"79":{"options":{"a":"Six","b":"eight","c":"Five","d":"Ten"},"question":"How many Principal Organs does United Nations has?","correctOption":"d"},"80":{"options":{"a":"1940","b":"1929","c":"1930","d":"1935"},"question":"In which year was the football World Cup held for the first time?","correctOption":"d"},"81":{"options":{"a":"Brazil","b":"Switzerland","c":"Russia","d":"Uruguay"},"question":"In  which  country  are  the  headquarters  of  FIFA   located?","correctOption":"d"},"82":{"options":{"a":"September 1, 1940A.D","b":"December 19, 1995 A.D","c":"December 14, 1955 A.D.","d":"October 20, 1950 A.D"},"question":"When Nepal did have the membership of UN?","correctOption":"c"},"83":{"options":{"a":"16","b":"19","c":"20","d":"15"},"question":"How many members are there in Security Council?","correctOption":"d"},"84":{"options":{"a":"India","b":"France","c":"Sweden","d":"Indonesia"},"question":"Which country passage the Budget two time in  a year","correctOption":"a"},"85":{"options":{"a":"Short Message Service","b":"System message server","c":"Speed message service","d":"Smart Message System"},"question":"What is the full form of SMS?","correctOption":"a"},"86":{"options":{"a":"japan","b":"Africa","c":"Australia","d":"Turkey"},"question":"Which country is know as land of Kangaroo?","correctOption":"b"},"87":{"options":{"a":"Mrs. Usha Bhatta","b":"Mrs. Luna Bhatta","c":"Mrs.Santi Malla","d":"Mrs. Shusila Sing"},"question":"Who is the first SLC lady Topper In Nepal?","correctOption":"c"},"88":{"options":{"a":"Mustang","b":"Taplejung","c":"Solukhumbu","d":"Manang"},"question":"Which is the coldest place of Nepal?","correctOption":"b"},"89":{"options":{"a":"Macchapuchre","b":"Manaslu","c":"Api Himalaya","d":"Kanchenjunga"},"question":"Which mountain is also called the killer mountain?","correctOption":"a"},"90":{"options":{"a":"Manang","b":"Mustang","c":"Dolpa","d":"taplejung"},"question":"Which district is known as the ‘district of desert’?","correctOption":"d"},"91":{"options":{"a":"Orville Wright and William Wright","b":"Paul Winchell","c":"Sir William Crookes","d":"William Stanley"},"question":"Who is the first AC transformer Inventors?","correctOption":"b"},"92":{"options":{"a":"W.A. Burt","b":"Galileo","c":"Garrett A.Morgan","d":"Geoge Estman"},"question":"Who is inventors of the Typewriter?","correctOption":"a"},"93":{"options":{"a":"Dec.7","b":"Dec.29","c":"May.1","d":"Oct.29"},"question":"When was international children day celebrated?","correctOption":"a"},"94":{"options":{"a":"Baishakh 26","b":"magh 19","c":"bhadra 1","d":"kartik 7"},"question":"When was the law day celebrated?","correctOption":"b"},"95":{"options":{"a":"Share market","b":"Computers","c":"Vehicles","d":"Human body"},"question":"“Blue Chips” is related to?","correctOption":"b"},"96":{"options":{"a":"28","b":"29","c":"30","d":"31"},"question":"How old was Jung Bahadur when he became the prime minster of Nepal?","correctOption":"c"},"97":{"options":{"a":"10","b":"20","c":"27","d":"30"},"question":"How many districts are there in the Terai region?","correctOption":"d"},"98":{"options":{"a":"Gandaki","b":"Mahakali","c":"Karnali","d":"Koshi"},"question":"Which river is known as sorrow of Bihar?","correctOption":"a"},"99":{"options":{"a":"Prithvi Narayan shah","b":"Junga Bahadur Rana","c":"Ganesh Man Sing","d":"Khila Raj Regmi"},"question":"Who is popular as “Lauha Purush”  of Nepal?","correctOption":"c"},"100":{"options":{"a":"Mediterranean","b":"Caspian","c":"Baltic","d":"Red"},"question":"Which sea lies on the west part of Syria?","correctOption":"d"}}